BRANDON P. HAMMOTHE

bhammoth@gmail.com | (312) 371-2593 | linkedin.com/in/brandonhammothe

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Resourceful, goal-oriented Quality Assurance Software Engineer with over 5 years of comprehensive experience in developing and servicing custom QA frameworks. Highly knowledgeable in systems analysis while executing business principles and processes. An enterprising leader that has led automation teams with excellent interpersonal and problem-solving skills. Exceptional skills include:

Cucumber

Selenium

Jenkins

Java

Ruby

SQL

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TEKsystems / MISO

Carmel, IN

2016 - 2016

QA Analyst II Contractor

Facilitated custom automation framework for Web, Windows, and API testing built in C#, Selenium, and TestStack.White, and collaborated with Agile teams for a regional energy grid management, not-for-profit organization.

- Established automation best practices that standardized how Agile teams wrote automated scripts.
- Wrote automation scripts to test energy grid efficiency.
- · Maintained automated test framework that tested Windows, Web, and API.
- Controlled the deployment and implementation of the custom framework for the company's Agile team environments.
- Assessed viability of the current UFT automated tests by examining quality of existing code and scripts.

Clinical Architecture

Carmel, IN

2015 - 2016

QA Automation Lead

Originated unit and integration tests using Visual Studio's test framework that ran in Jenkins, developed Web UI Automation platform using Selenium, Java, and Cucumber, and managed the best practice documents for a medical terminology software startup.

- Evaluated UI Automation frameworks against company software and presented results to the Director of QA.
- Developed unit tests that reduced bugs by 50%.
- Supervised dozens of JIRA workflow tickets between the Development Team and QA daily.
- Wrote 15-20 manual test cases along with conducting exploratory testing of .NET applications daily.
- Engineered and executed smoke tests that diminished critical bugs in a production environment.

E-gineering LLC. / Cook Research Institute

West Lafayette, IN

2014 - 2015

Automation Architect Contractor

Brandon Hammothe Page Two

Built a framework with VBScript in UFT that supported web applications for document and workflow management systems for a medical device company.

- Formulated automated tests utilizing UFT that replaced manual tests, reducing testing time by 80%.
- Formalized automation best practices to ensure reusability and efficiency for QA team members.
- Researched automated testing tools to best suit client's needs and technical requirements.
- Constructed a review process for non-technical personnel to assess automation scripts for coverage.

Blackboard Inc. Indianapolis, IN 2012 – 2013

Quality Assurance Automation Engineer

Authored and managed automated tests for a large, learning management system using Java, Selenium, and Fitnesse that supported the in-house testing framework for an education technology company.

- Reduced manual testing to 20% by utilizing Fitnesse scripts that ran using the Selenium Web Driver to test latest build.
- Maximized time of testing user permissions by 95% by utilizing Blackboard's API.
- Expedited test development by using the pair-programming agile methodology.
- Collaborated with developers, UX/UI team, and business analysts to create test plans that encompassed new features and regression.
- Taught 20 non-technical QA leads and analysts object oriented programming (OOP) and Java in weekly meetings.

Wabash National Lafayette, IN 2010 – 2011

Application Developer

Established a web application using C# .NET that created financial quotes for tractor trailers and headed a product demonstration focusing on increasing customer satisfaction and boosting efficiency for a transportation company.

- Initiated a quote maintenance system in .NET framework that replaced a 20-year-old manual process.
- Established gueries using LINQ to SQL to enforce front-end database rules.
- Planned and executed an independent Application Developer interview with a prospective Application Developer intern.

EDUCATION

Masters of Science Technology and Leadership, Biometrics Expected completion date of August, 2017 Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN

Bachelors of Science in Computer Information Technology, Information Systems Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN